Finding Aid for the Leo Smit Slide Collection, circa 1966-1991
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Leo Smit Slide Collection, circa 1966-1991
Mus. Arc. 6.4
Smit, Leo, 1921-1999
29 boxes ( 13,704 35 millimeter slides )
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library.
The Leo Smit Slide Collection contains approximately 13,705 35 millimeter slides taken by American composer, Leo Smit. The contents include images of notable musicians, images used in his lecture recitals, and images taken during his many journeys in the United States and abroad, including Central and South America, Italy, and various other European countries.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Administrative Information
Acquisition Information
Gift of Nils Vigeland, 2011.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Biographical Note
Leo Smit was born to Russian immigrants on January 12, 1921, in Philadelphia. He received his earliest musical training from his father, Kolman Smit, beginning at age five. Kolman Smit was a professional violinist who performed in the Philadelphia Orchestra (1926-1931) under Leopold Stokowski, the Cincinnati Symphony under Fritz Reiner, and the NBC Symphony under Arturo Toscanini.
After private piano studies with Martha Lantner, Joseph Wissof, and Bert Shefter, Smit traveled to Moscow with his mother in 1929 to study piano for three months with Dmitri Kabalevsky on scholarship at the Moscow Conservatory. Upon his return to Philadelphia, Smit received a scholarship in 1930 to study piano at Curtis Institute of Music with noted piano pedagogue Isabelle Vengerova. He continued his studies on scholarship in New York, studying piano with José Iturbi (1933-35) and composition with Nicolas Nabokov (1935). It was under Nabokov's tutelage that Smit produced his first original composition in 1935, Zvay, a song setting of a Yiddish poem by Mani Loeb for soprano and piano.
Smit began his professional career as a pianist while still in his teens. His first professional engagement was as rehearsal pianist for George Balanchine's American Ballet Company in 1936-37. A year after beginning in this position, Smit met Igor Stravinsky during rehearsals of the composer's ballet, Jeu de Cartes. Smit gave his debut recital as a solo pianist at Carnegie Hall in February 1939. His successful debut was followed by a concert tour of the United States in 1940.
Leo Smit's career as composer, pianist, conductor, and educator spanned seven decades of musical life in the United States. He established close working relationships, and/or friendships, with many of the most prominent musicians of the 20th century, including Igor Stravinsky, Béla Bartók, Aaron Copland, Leonard Bernstein, Harold Shapero, William Schuman, Alex Haieff, Leopold Stokowski, and Lukas Foss. As a performer, Smit was an enthusiastic and persuasive advocate and interpreter of the music of his time, especially the solo piano music of Aaron Copland. His compositional output totals more than one hundred works, including two operas, three symphonies, more than ninety songs, two ballets, and numerous chamber and piano works.
Smit was also a talented photographer. In addition to the many photographs he took of noted musicians, Smit also used his skill as a photographer to capture images from his travels. Many of his travel pictures reflect his reverence for nature. As part of his innovative approach to programming, Smit would often include displays of his photography in his theme-based concerts.
During his career Leo Smit earned several awards and honors, including Fulbright (piano) and Guggenheim (composition) Fellowships in 1950, a fellowship at the American Academy in Rome for 1950-51, the Boston Symphony Merit Award in 1953 for his Symphony No. 1 (premiered October 16, 1953 by the Boston Symphony Orchestra, conducted by Charles Munch), the New York Critics Circle Award in 1957 (also for his Symphony No. 1), his selection as an artist for a State Department concert tour of Latin America in 1967-68, and the Buffalo Evening News Man of the Year award in 1969. As an educator, Smit held positions at Sarah Lawrence College (1947-49), UCLA (1957-63), and the State University of New York at Buffalo (1962-84).
Leo Smit died December 12, 1999 in Scripps Hospital, Encinitas, California.
Scope and Content Note
The Leo Smit Slide Collection contains approximately 13,705 35 millimeter slides taken by American composer, Leo Smit. The contents include: images of notable musicians, including Leonard Bernstein, Aaron Copland, William Schuman, Virgil Thomson, Roger Sessions, Jan Williams, Charles Wuorinen, and Lejaren Hiller; images used in his lecture recitals, including sets of images for his lectures Liszt in Italy and Liszt in Rome; and images taken during his many journeys in the United States and abroad, including Central and South America, Italy, and various other European countries.
Arrangement
Contents of this collection have not been analyzed at the item level. The collection was received in containers and trays that had been marked by Leo Smit to identify sets and groups of subject matter. His original order has been preserved at that level but re-organized to form series of similar subject matter based on geographic locations. Additional series were created to accommodate sets that were not suited to a geographic category. There is redundancy and overlap among some series due to the decision to preserve Smit's original groupings. The first series of images of people will be described more fully in the future.
The collection is arranged in six series:
I. People
II. Europe
III. United States
IV. Central/South America
V. Liszt in Italy
VI. Miscellaneous
VII. Additions
Container List
- People, undated, I.; 300 slides
  - People, undated (Box 1)
    Musicians, undated (199 slides)
    Miscellaneous, undated (40 slides)
    Unidentified, undated (61 slides)
- Europe, 1967-1988, II.; Box 2-Box 9
  Arranged into three subseries:
  Italy
  Italy/Europe
  Europe
  - Italy, 1971-1988, A.; Box 2-Box 4
    - Italy (1), 1971-1988, 450 slides (Box 2)
      St. L’Arch, 1988 (30 slides)
      Florence, undated (39 slides)
      Rome, 1971 (21 slides)
      Rome, undated (49 slides)
      Villa Bourgese, 1971 (22 slides)
      Gaelerie Bourgese, 1988 (35 slides)
      Villa d’Este, 1985 (51 slides)
      Apollo/Daphne, 1988 (27 slides)
      Roman Forum, 1988 (33 slides)
      Palatine Bocca and Verta Bells, 1985 (29 slides)
      Miscellaneous, undated (114 slides)
    - Italy (2), 1971-1985, 346 slides (Box 3)
      St. Peters, 1985 (26 slides)
      St. Peters, undated (27 slides)
      Navona, 1985 (28 slides)
      Navona, undated (50 slides)
      St. Clement, undated (25 slides)
      St. Stefano Rotunda, 1985 (39 slides)
      Aventive, Sheila, Alexei Haieff, and Florence, 1985 (41 slides)
      Cap. Museum, 1985 (28 slides)
      Pisa, Como, 1971 (25 slides)
      St. John Latera, 1985 (29 slides)
      P. del Popolo, 1985 (28 slides)
    - Italy (3), 1971-1985, 544 slides (Box 4)
      Rome, undated (308 slides)
      Venice, undated (24 slides)
      Firenze, 1971 (21 slides)
      Pisa, 1985 (22 slides)
      Assisi, 1971 (24 slides)
      Villa d’Este, 1973 (35 slides)
      Sienna, 1971 (20 slides)
      Umbria, 1971 (17 slides)
      Pompeii, 1972 (73 slides)
  - Italy/Europe, 1971-1987, B.; Box 5-Box 7
    - Italy/Europe (1), 1971-1985, 319 slides (Box 5)
      Trajan MKT, undated (48 slides)
      Clouters, 1985 (38 slides)
      Hersu Caneum, 1972 (40 slides)
      St. Daltas, Porter Grave, undated (9 slides)
      [Unlisted], 1971 (24 slides)
      Pompeii, 1972 (14 slides)
      V. Medici, Aventive, 1980 (21 slides)
      Ephesus, St. John, 1973 (38 slides)
      Ippicio, Busts (Pinicio), 1980 (23 slides)
      Terme Museo, 1980 (25 slides)
      Funeral Boats, Cimitero Angels, 1985 (13 slides)
      Florence, David, 1985 (26 slides)
    - Italy/Europe (2), 1971-1980, 463 slides (Box 6)
      Arigento, 1973 (73 slides)
      Rome, 1971 (49 slides)
      Rome/Pisa, 1972 (11 slides)
      Rome, 1980 (15 slides)
      Rome, 1972 (15 slides)
      Rome, 1972 (38 slides)
      Rome, 1971 (25 slides)
      Rome/Borromimi, 1971 (27 slides)
      St. Peters/Villa Medici, 1980 (21 slides)
      Rome, 1971 (15 slides)
      M. Aurelius, 1980 (35 slides)
      Taormina, 1973 (41 slides)
      Bellagio, 1971 (40 slides)
      Villa d’Este, 1980 (58 slides)
    - Italy/Europe (3), 1971-1987, 309 slides (Box 7)
      St. Peters, 1971 (39 slides)
      St. Peters, 1980 (24 slides)
      St. Peters, 1985 (17 slides)
      Athens, 1973 (39 slides)
      [Unlabeled], 1980 (22 slides)
      Quirinale Horses/ P. Navona Foat, 1980 (12 slides)
      Esedva/Navona/Horses, 1985 (12 slides)
      Venice, 1980 (31 slides)
      Venice, 1971 (18 slides)
      Venice, 1981 (15 slides)
      Expo, 1987 (80 slides)
  - Europe, 1967-1985, C.; Box 8-Box 9
    - Europe (1), 1972-1981, 401 slides (Box 8)
      Spain, 1973 (35 slides)
      Slovenia, 1981 (14 slides)
      Croatia, 1973 (69 slides)
      Yugoslavia, 1981 (53 slides)
      Greece, 1973 (93 slides)
      Turkey, 1972-73 (137 slides)
    - Europe (2), 1967-1985, 340 slides (Box 9)
      Belgrade, 1980 (39 slides)
      Forum, 1980 (23 slides)
      Beta tu…?, 1971 (30 slides)
      Venice, undated (59 slides)
      Stonehenge, 1980 (40 slides)
      SS Paul & John, Gregory Cathedrals, 1985 (30 slides)
      Venice, undated (19 slides)
      Tortoise Fount., 1980 (18 slides)
      Venezia, 1985 (17 slides)
      Venice, undated (28 slides)
      Miscellaneous, 1982 (22 slides)
      Zion, 1967 (15 slides)
- United States, 1967-1990, III.; Box 10-Box 17
  California/Alaska
  Southwestern United States
  Eastern United States
  - California/Alaska, 1967-1989, A.; Box 10-Box 12
    - California (1), 1969-1987, 499 slides (Box 10)
      California, undated (88 slides)
      San Francisco (Anne Bloomfield), 1969-71 (30 slides)
      California - Gulls, undated (102 slides)
      California – Hummingbirds, undated (19 slides)
      California - Sunsets, 1987 (66 slides)
      San Diego – Whales, 1977 (18 slides)
      Palm Springs, 1977 (49 slides)
      Solana Beach, 1978 (22 slides)
      Masson Vineyards, 1970 (15 slides)
      Leucadia, undated (90 slides)
    - California (2), 1967-1989, 332 slides (Box 11)
      Leucadia, 1987 (7 slides)
      Solana Beach, 1980 (7 slides)
      California sunsets, undated (19 slides)
      Palm Springs, 1967 (8 slides)
      Leucadia sunsets, 1987 (20 slides)
      California sunsets, 1989 (18 slides)
      California sunsets, 1986-87 (209 slides)
      California sunsets, undated (13 slides)
      Mother Lode, California, 1971 (31 slides)
    - California/Alaska, 1969-1989, 457 slides (Box 12)
      California
      Pacific Grove, 1971 (19 slides)
      Leucadia house, 1987 (17 slides)
      California sunsets, 1990 (33 slides)
      San Diego, 1987 (31 slides)
      Leucadia sunsets, 1989 (27 slides)
      San Diego, 1970 (8 slides)
      Alaska
      Sitka, 1969 (31 slides)
      Seattle-Alaska, 1969 (84 slides)
      Anchorage, 1969 (25 slides)
      Ketchikan, 1969 (12 slides)
      Juneau, 1969 (37 slides)
      Sitka, 1969 (24 slides)
      Mt. McKinley, 1969 (49 slides)
      Alaska – miscellaneous, 1969 (60 slides)
  - Southwest United States, 1967-1991, B.; Box 13-Box 16
    - Southwest United States (1), 1969-1991, 424 slides (Box 13)
      Crater Lake, 1969 (18 slides)
      Southwest (miscellaneous), 1971 (29 slides)
      Copper mine, Mesa Verde, 1970 (12 slides)
      Enchanted Mesa, 1970 (24 slides)
      Taos, 1988 (33 slides)
      Misc., 1971 (28 slides)
      Southwest (miscellaneous), 1973 (31 slides)
      Grand Canyon, 1973 (35 slides)
      Canyon de Chelly, 1986 (18 slides)
      California Redwoods, 1978 (21 slides)
      California sunsets, 1988 (28 slides)
      Grand Canyon, 1990 (23 slides)
      Pacific Grove, 1969 (11 slides)
      Oraibi, 1970 (12 slides)
      California sunsets, 1991 (24 slides)
      Coldwater, 1971 (29 slides)
      California, 1989 (16 slides)
      Mother Lode, California, 1971 (32 slides)
    - Southwest United States (2), 1969-1990, 498 slides (Box 14)
      Grand Canyon, 1972, 1973, 1977 (70 slides)
      Grand Canyon – Kaibal Trail, 1972 (32 slides)
      Grand Canyon – West Rim, 1972, 1985 (47 slides)
      Grand Canyon – Sunsets, 1972, 1990 (49 slides)
      Lake Powell, 1969, 1972 (59 slides)
      Walnut Canyon, 1970 (13 slides)
      Canyon de Chelly, Navajo Reservation, 1972 (33 slides)
      Goldwater Kachinas, 1971 (36 slides)
      Miscellaneous, 1970 (39 slides)
      Montezuma’s Castle, 1970 (13 slides)
      Canyon de Chelly, Horses, undated (24 slides)
      Canyon de Chelly, Hopi Mesas, undated (4 slides)
      Grand Canyon, undated (79 slides)
    - Southwest United States (3), 1968-1988, 773 slides (Box 15)
      Grand Canyon; Mesa Verde, 1972 (17 slides)
      Yosemite, 1972 (16 slides)
      Mesa Verde glyphs, 1972 (19 slides)
      White Sands; Oraibi, 1986 (20 slides)
      Grand Canyon, 1967 (18 slides)
      Death Valley, 1972 (17 slides)
      Canyon de Chelly, 1972 (5 slides)
      Southwest (miscellaneous), undated (74 slides)
      Utah
      Arches National Park, 1968 (55 slides)
      Bryce Canyon, 1968 (28 slides)
      Capitol Reef Monument, 1968 (25 slides)
      Dead Horse Viewpoint, 1968 (13 slides)
      Moab, 1968 (33 slides)
      Zion National Park, 1968 (34 slides)
      New Mexico
      Three Rivers, White Sands, 1970-71 (142 slides)
      Gran Quivira, 1973-74 (66 slides)
      Puye Dancers, 1976 (32 slides)
      Taos, 1988 (35 slides)
      Aztec, undated (39 slides)
      Aerial views – Nevada, Arizona, 1972 (16 slides)
      Virginia City, Nevada, 1970 (21 slides)
      Southwest United States – Miscellaneous, undated (48 slides)
    - Southwest United States (4), 1967-1986, 647 slides (Box 16)
      Salt Lake City, 1969 (29 slides)
      Santa Fe, 1970 (16 slides)
      Salt Lake, 1977 (13 slides)
      White Sands, 1974 (37 slides)
      Kachinas, 1971 (20 slides)
      Mother Lode, 1971 (9 slides)
      Arizona, New Mexico, California, Louisiana, 1982 (29 slides)
      Utah, 1968 (31 slides)
      Zion, 1982 (23 slides)
      Grand Canyon, 1967-69 (51 slides)
      Oak Creek Canyon, 1967-70 (20 slides)
      Tucson Desert Museum, 1967-70 (15 slides)
      Wild Horse Ranch, 1969 (30 slides)
      Grand Canyon, 1967 (5 slides)
      Arizona (miscellaneous), 1967-70 (36 slides)
      Grand Canyon, 1985 (34 slides)
      Grand Canyon, 1985 (35 slides)
      Grand Canyon, 1972 (16 slides)
      Oraibi, 1985 (30 slides)
      Arches Park, 1968 (34 slides)
      Grand Canyon, 1986 (31 slides)
      Grand Canyon, 1985 (33 slides)
  - Eastern United States, 1967-1984, C.; 554 slides
    - Eastern United States, 1967-1984 (Box 17)
      Niagara Falls, 1967-69 (109 slides)
      Buffalo, New York, 1966-69 (72 slides)
      New York City, 1969-70 (12 slides)
      Miscellaneous, 1975 (70 slides)
      Maine; Portsmouth, New Hampshire, 1984 (32 slides)
      National Gallery, Washington D.C., 1971 (16 slides)
      Asheville, Virginia, 1980 (19 slides)
      Pisgah Forest, North Carolina, 1980 (19 slides)
      Florida, 1972, 1983 (55 slides)
      Serpent Mound, Ohio, 1976 (18 slides)
      Niagara Falls, 1983 (9 slides)
      Fort Kearney, Virginia, 1970 (20 slides)
      Albany, 1980 (20 slides)
      Everglades, 1972 (28 slides)
      Lexington, Virginia, 1967-72 (35 slides)
      Miscellaneous, undated (20 slides)
- Central/South America, 1967-1986, IV.; Box 18-Box 20
  - Central/South America (1), 1967-1976, 670 slides (Box 18)
    Latin American Tour, 1967 (78 slides)
    Latin American Tour II, undated (136 slides)
    Latin American Tour - People, 1968 (30 slides)
    El Morro, Puerto Rico, 1971 (38 slides)
    Mexico – Uxmal, 1976 (57 slides)
    Mexico – Chichen-Itza, 1976 (40 slides)
    Mexico – Yucatan, 1976 (22 slides)
    Guatemala, 1968 (37 slides)
    Columbia, 1968 (11 slides)
    Ecuador, 1968 (46 slides)
    Peru, 1968 (99 slides)
    Bolivia, 1968 (22 slides)
    Chile, 1968 (17 slides)
    Miscellaneous, 1967-68 (37 slides)
  - Central/South America (2), 1967-1976, 376 slides (Box 19)
    Santo Domingo, 1967 (13 slides)
    Kingston/ Cartleton Gardens/ Gagnes, 1967 (14 slides)
    Caracas, 1967 (9 slides)
    Sinamaico and Maracaibo, 1967 (11 slides)
    Puerto la Cruz and Boat to Maragarita, 1967 (7 slides)
    Margarita, Venezuela, 1967 (12 slides)
    Trinidad, 1967 (18 slides)
    Caroni Swamp, 1967 (7 slides)
    South America, 1967 (24 slides)
    Brasilia, 1967 (12 slides)
    Belem, 1967 (14 slides)
    Sao Paulo, 1967 (9 slides)
    Montevideo, 1967 (9 slides)
    Salto, 1967 (15 slides)
    Cordoba, Argentina, 1967 (12 slides)
    Tucaman, 1967 (11 slides)
    Asuncion, 1967 (15 slides)
    Mexico City, 1968 (18 slides)
    South America (miscellaneous), 1967-68 (81 slides)
    Uxmal, 1976 (15 slides)
    Bogota, 1968 (21 slides)
    Petroglyphs, 1973 (29 slides)
  - Central/South America (3), 1967-1986, 484 slides (Box 20)
    Machu Picchu, 1968 (21 slides)
    Grand Canyon, 1986 (62 slides)
    Bolivia; Mexico, 1968 (27 slides)
    Mexico, 1976 (8 slides)
    Central America (miscellaneous), 1968 (59 slides)
    Bolivia, 1968 (61 slides)
    Lower Manhattan, 1983 (11 slides)
    San Jose, 1968 (28 slides)
    Copan, 1967, 1978 (27 slides)
    Central America, 1968 (60 slides)
    Peru, 1968 (22 slides)
    South America, 1967-68 (37 slides)
    Ecuador, 1967-68 (61 slides)
- Liszt in Italy, 1967-1989, V.; Box 21-Box 22
  Arranged into two subseries:
  Liszt in Italy
  Liszt in Rome
  - Liszt in Italy, 1967-1989, A.; 810 slides
    - Liszt in Italy, 1967-1989 (Box 21)
      Villa d’Este, undated (112 slides)
      Gondola, undated (107 slides)
      Canzonetta, undated (99 slides)
      Pensierosa, undated (45 slides)
      Little Piece, undated (7 slides)
      Sursum corda, undated (71 slides)
      Liszt in Italy Presentation Slides, undated (71 slides)
      Liszt in Italy, 1985 (66 slides)
      Liszt in Italy, 1967 (16 slides)
      Liszt, 1989 (17 slides)
      Liszt in Italy, undated (3 slides)
      Liszt in Italy, 1980 (7 slides)
      Liszt in Italy, 1971 (11 slides)
      Liszt in Italy, 1985 (30 slides)
      Liszt in Italy, undated (141 slides)
  - Liszt in Rome, 1971-1972, B.; 701 slides
    - Liszt in Rome, 1971-1972 (Box 22)
      Liszt in Rome, 1971 (199 slides)
      Liszt (miscellaneous), 1971 (14 slides)
      Bells, 1971 (12 slides)
      Tombs, 1971 (13 slides)
      Villa d’Este, 1971 (29 slides)
      Tristan, 1971 (16 slides)
      Sursum corda, 1971 (14 slides)
      Liszt (unlabeled), 1971 (26 slides)
      Cosa, 1971 (20 slides)
      Brown, 1971 (17 slides)
      Fountains, 1971 (37 slides)
      Stendhal Romanticism, Arches, 1971 (19 slides)
      Martial, 1971 (18 slides)
      Horace, 1971 (17 slides)
      Daphne & Apollo, 1972 (18 slides)
      Michelangelo, 1971 (4 slides)
      Menine, 1971 (18 slides)
      Rome (unlabeled), 1971 (37 slides)
      Cass. Hill, 1971 (16 slides)
      Rome miscellaneous, 1971 (157 slides)
- Miscellaneous, 1966-1989, VI.; Box 23-Box 29
  Cities
  Compartment Files
  Miscellaneous
  - Cities, 1967-1969, A.; 209 slides
    - Cities, 1967-1969 (Box 23)
      Charleston, South Carolina, 1969 (35 slides)
      Lexington, Kentucky, 1968 (14 slides)
      Nashville, Tennessee, 1968 (15 slides)
      St. Louis, Missouri, 1967-69 (20 slides)
      Seattle, Washington, 1966 (16 slides)
      Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania; Concord, Massachusetts; Boston, Massachusetts, 1967-69 (18 slides)
      Washington D.C., 1966-69 (18 slides)
      Halifax, Nova Scotia, 1967-69 (19 slides)
      New York City, 1967-69 (35 slides)
      Disneyland, California, 1968 (19 slides)
  - Compartment Files, 1966-1987, B.; Box 24-Box 25
    - Compartment Files (1), 1966-1987, 663 slides (Box 24)
      Ventura House, Laver, Morris G., California, undated (23 slides)
      Ventura House, Laver, Morris G., California, 1966 (4 slides)
      Ventura House, Laver, Morris G., California, 1967 (4 slides)
      Ventura House, Laver, Morris G., California, 1968 (29 slides)
      Ventura House, Laver, Morris G., California, 1968 (2 slides)
      Ventura House, Laver, Morris G., California, 1968 (12 slides)
      Ventura House, Laver, Morris G., California, 1969 (31 slides)
      Ventura House, Laver, Morris G., California, 1969 (8 slides)
      Ventura House, Laver, Morris G., California, 1970 (2 slides)
      Ventura House, Laver, Morris G., California, 1970 (3 slides)
      Ventura House, Laver, Morris G., California, 1976 (1 slides)
      Ventura House, Laver, Morris G., California, 1977 (1 slides)
      Ventura House, Laver, Morris G., California, 1977 (3 slides)
      Ventura House, Laver, Morris G., California, 1984 (1 slides)
      Ventura House, Laver, Morris G., California, 1986 (3 slides)
      Ventura House, Laver, Morris G., California, 1986 (8 slides)
      Ventura House, Laver, Morris G., California, 1986 (22 slides)
      Ventura House, Laver, Morris G., California, 1987 (21 slides)
      Ventura House, Laver, Morris G., California, 1987 (5 slides)
      Ventura House, Laver, Morris G., California, 1987 (7 slides)
      Ventura House, Laver, Morris G., California, 1987 (1 slides)
      Ostia Antica, 1971 (132 slides)
      Ostia Antica, 1971 (53 slides)
      Istanbul, 1977 (174 slides)
      Rome/Haiti, 1975 (113 slides)
    - Compartment Files (2), 1967-1986, 474 slides (Box 25)
      Rome/Haiti, 1975 (58 slides)
      Latin/South America, 1967 (67 slides)
      Latin/South America, 1968 (112 slides)
      Alaska/Fort Ross, 1969 (87 slides)
      Zoos, 1968, 1969, 1970 (9 slides)
      Zoos, 1968, 1970 (9 slides)
      Zoos, 1968, 1986 (26 slides)
      Zoos, 1969, 1970 (28 slides)
      Zoos, 1967 (40 slides)
      Zoos, 1967, 1970 (19 slides)
      Zoos, 1970 (1 slides)
      Zoos, 1967 (13 slides)
      Zoos, 1968 (5 slides)
  - Miscellaneous, 1967-1991, C.; Box 26-Box 29
    - Miscellaneous (1), 1967-1969, 249 slides (Box 26)
      Letchworth Park, 1967-68 (97 slides)
      Corning Glass Museum, 1969 (15 slides)
      Nancy Bergama, 1969 (14 slides)
      Pascals, 1969 (12 slides)
      Hydroplanes, 1969 (12 slides)
      [Unlabeled], 1969 (45 slides)
      Japanese Gardens, 1969 (20 slides)
      Miscellaneous, 1969 (34 slides)
    - Miscellaneous (2), undated, 394 slides (Box 27)
      Angelus, undated (91 slides)
      Funerailles, undated (98 slides)
      Miserere, undated (28 slides)
      Bells, undated (66 slides)
      Love Dream, undated (75 slides)
      Consolata, undated (36 slides)
    - Miscellaneous (3), 1967-1989, 387 slides (Box 28)
      Mephisto Waltz movie set, 1970 (27 slides)
      Colts vs. Bills game, 1971 (27 slides)
      Last class, UB; Letchworth State Park, 1983 (25 slides)
      Hot Air Balloons, 1997 (16 slides)
      Emily Dickinson Grave, Amherst, Massachusetts, 1989 (21 slides)
      Cole Porter Grave, Peru, Indiana, 1976 (17 slides)
      L.S. Sunsets, 1969 (23 slides)
      Art, undated (18 slides)
      Leo Smit, 1967 (51 slides)
      Lion Safari, 1972 (64 slides)
      [Unlabeled], undated (98 slides)
    - Miscellaneous (4), 1969-1991, 631 slides (Box 29)
      Giraffes, elephants, 1986 (37 slides)
      Safari – animals, 1972 (32 slides)
      San Diego Zoo, 1986 (20 slides)
      Wild animals, 1986 (37 slides)
      Birds, 1984 (22 slides)
      Florida – pelicans, 1978 (14 slides)
      Wild animals – gorillas, 1986 (35 slides)